<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../../Documents/GitHub/BallotandMe/docs/playSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
    <head>
        <title>Langston Hughes, pages 13-17</title>
        <editor>McKenna Ballew</editor>
    </head>
    <body>
    <div1>
        <!--PAGE 13-->
        <sp>
    <speaker>NARRATOR (ctd)</speaker>
<dialogue>
    <p><lb/><insert hand="LH">He was</insert>a friend of Presidents. That man was the great founder of
        <lb/>Tuskegee Institute, Book T. Washington.</p>
</dialogue>
        </sp>
            <stage type="enter">
                <lb/>(ENTER WASHINGTON)
            </stage>
        <sp>
   <speaker>WASHINTON:</speaker>
           <dialogue>
            <p>
               <lb/>Friends, the individual<insert hand="LH">or</insert> race that owns the property, pays the
               <lb/>taxes, possesses the intelligence and substantial character, is
               <lb/>the one which is going to exercise the greatest control in
               <lb/>government, whether he lives in the North or whether he lives in
               <lb/>the South. There is no defense or security for any of us except
               <lb/>in the highest intelligence and development of all. Education must
               <lb/>be digested and assimilated in order to make it significant. The
               <lb/>science, the art, the literature that fails to reach down and bring
               <lb/>the humblest . up to the enjoyment of the fullest blessings of our
               <lb/>government is weak, no matter how costly the buildings or apparatus
               <lb/>used, or how modern the methods of instruction employed. The study
               <lb/>of arithmetic that does not result in making men conscientious in
               <lb/>receiving and counting the ballots of their fellow men is faulty.
            </p>
           </dialogue>
        </sp>
        <sp>
            <speaker>NARRATOR:</speaker>
            <dialogue>
                <p>
                    <lb/>Unfortunately, the unreconstructed rebels of the South continued to
                    <lb/>deny the rights to vote, or failed to count, the ballots of Negro
                    <lb/>citizens at the turn of the century. When Charles H. White left
                    <lb/>Congress in 1901, it was more than a quarter of a century before we
                    <lb/>had there another national representative. In 1928 Oscar DePriest
                    <lb/>was elected to Congress from the First Illinois District -- being
                    <lb/>the first Northern Negro over to sit in the national legislature. 
                    <lb/>As the great migrations from the South increased after each war,
                    <lb/>and the black populations of our Northern industrial cities grew,
                    <lb/>so Negro political power grew. Manicipal judges, city councilmen,
                    <lb/>county officials,  and state legislators of color from New York to
                    <lb/>Los Angeles became not uncommon. From Illinois, Arthur W. Michell
                </p>
            </dialogue>
        </sp>
        </div1>
        <!--PAGE 14-->
        <div1>
        <sp>
            <speaker>NARRATOR (ctd.)</speaker>
            <dialogue>
                <p>
                    <lb/>FOLLOWED De Priest to Congress, then came William L. Dawson
                    <lb/>serving now. From New York Adam Clayton Powell, Jr. was elected
                    <lb/>in 1945, and most recently<insert hand="LH">Charles C</insert>Diggs of Detroit became the 27th man
                    <lb/>of color to sit in Congresss. There should be more -- more
                    <lb/>Powells, Dawsons, and Diggses in Washington. More <insert hand="LH">James</insert>Watsons and
                    <lb/>Bessie Buchanans in state governments<insert hand="LH">as in New York.</insert>More Hulan Jacks in more
                    <lb/>American city halls<insert hand="LH">as in Manhantton</insert>and more judges such as Hivers, Paige, Stevens,
                    <lb/>Dickens and JaneBolin on the benches of municipalities across the
                    <lb/>nation. And we all -- you, me -- must use our vote wisely and
                    <lb/>use it well to elect to all sorts of offices, particularly the
                    <lb/>national officies, men who will bring to bear<insert hand="LH">our democratic forces</insert>on all public officials
                    <lb/>to not only open up -- but to <underline>protect</underline>u --
                    <lb/>the ballow boxes of the South -- so that Negro citizens may
                    <lb/>vote in Mississippi and Georgia and Alabama and South Carolina
                    <lb/>again -- and again sent to Congress <underline>from the South</underline> black men --
                </p>
            </dialogue>
        </sp>
        <stage type="action">
            <lb/>(A WOMAN CRIES FROM THE AUDIENCE)
        </stage>
            <sp>
                <speaker>SOJOURNER:</speaker>
                <dialogue>
                    <p>
                     <lb/>And black women?
                    </p>
                </dialogue>
             </sp>
            <stage type="action">
                <lb/>(SOJURNER TRUTH RISES AND JOINS THE OTHERS ON THE
                <lb/>PLATFORM)
            </stage>
            
        </div1>
    </body>
 </root>