<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--1st page-->
<!-- Should mark-up the text in the middle of the page:--> 
<!--The top right of the page "AUTHOR'S COPY": --> 
<!-- Handwritten note at the bottom of the first page: -->

<!--2nd page-->
<!-- Recognize Characters: -->
<xml>
                                <p>CHARACTERS</p>
                        <p>(In order of appearance)</p>
<castGroup rend="braced">
    <castItem>
        <role>Representatives in Congress during Reconstruction</role>
        <actors>
        Frederick Doughlass
        Jefferson P. Lono
        Joseph H. Rainey
        Robert O. DeLARGE    
        Alonzo J. Rainer
        Robert B. Elliot 
        </actors>
    </castItem>
    <castItem>
        <role>Senators<date>1879-1881</date></role>
        <actors>
            <!--hard to read names-->
        </actors>
    </castItem>
    <castItem>
        <role>Represenatatives<date>1883-1897</date></role>
        <actors>
            JOHN M. LANGSTON
            THOMAS E. MILLER
            GEORGE W. MURRAY
            JAMES E. O`HARA
            HENRY Y. OHEATHAM
            GEORGE H. WHITE
            BOOKER T. WASHINGTON
        </actors>
    </castItem>
</castGroup>
<!--The right side of the page has an address & date-->
<note>NOTE: Speaking parts are marked with asterikes.** All except Sojurner Truth may read speeches from rostrum, and even she may read her long speech, but should learn rest of dialogue. Fraunces has only one line. "And I voted."</note>

<!-- 3rd page -->
                    <heading>THE BALLOT AND ME</heading>
<setting>A rostrum</setting>
<time>The present, with flashbacks</time>
<action>A Narrator comes to the rostrum and shouts four words very loudy as if opening a Town Meeting.</action>
<p>
   NARRATOR: Ballot!
             Sufferage!
             Franchise!
             Vote!
             <!-- right of page words -->
</p>
<p>
   (NARRATOR BANGS HIS GAVEL)
    The dictionary says:
    <Definition Ballot="underlined">"Ballot---the method of secret voting; 
        orgininally means of mall balls placed in an urn or box."</Definition>  
    <Definition Sufferage="underlined">"Suffrage---a vote given by a member of
        a body, state, or society, in assent to a propostion or in favor of the
        election of a person."</Definition>
    <Definition Franchise="underlined">"Franchise---the right of voting at
        public elections."</Definition>
    <Definition Vote="underlined">"Vote---an intimation that one approve or
        disapproves, accepts or rejects, a proposal, motion, candidate for
        office, or the like."</Definition>
</p>
    <Narrator>NARRATOR (cont'd):<p>The right to cast a bllot, to exercise suffarage, to vote is one of the basic
rights of citizens in a democracy--a democracy,
that form of government in which control is
vested in the people as a whole. The ballot 
is basic</p>
<p>Negro Americans---you, me---are very much a
part of this democracy. We're 15 million---
and our vote counts. From the national to
the local level <word your="underlined">your</word> vote counts. It counts
in more and better jobs---in diplomatic posts
abroad to local political patronage.
It counts in education, housing, in civil
rights, in cleaner streets, in better garbage
collection. The vote has value.
Don't neglect your right to vote. Don't waste it.
Don't forget it.</p>
<p>Maybe all of us would value the right of
sufferage more if we stopped to look back a
moment at what the struggle for the vote has
cost. Back in the Middle Ages few people
had control over their own lives, let alone
over the land or the country. Kings and
barons and chiefs and over-lords ran every-
thing and everybody. Then came the Magna Carta 
in <date>1215</date>in<country>England,</country>and almost 400</p></Narrator>
    <!--5th page-->
    <Narrator>NARRATOR (cont'd): <p>years later the Bill of Rights, many of whose provisions were incorporated into
our own Consitution in <date>1787</date>and into the
American Bill of Rights in <date>1791</date> Some of
those rights, we, the Negro people of America,
are still trying to secure in full.</p>
<p>We came to these shores first as explorers--- 
with Cortez, with Balboa, with Columbus. But 
we did not migrate in large numbers. The
majority of our ancestors were brought to the
Americas by force as slaves, dating from <date>1619.</date>
Slaves, like serfs in Europe, could not vote.
But very early in our history, after the 
colonies won their freedom from the British---
Crispus Attucks of Boston, a Negro, being
the first man killed when resistance to the
Brith started--free Negroes in the New
England colonies voted. Some Negroes in our
country have always voted from the very be-
ginning of our United States, and fought
to keep the vote and extend it to others.
But sometimes it was a hard battle. You who
have the vote here in New York, keep it, use
it, and help others to get it.
After the Revolutinary War, free Negroes
could vote anywhere, but in <date>1789</date>the Southern
salve-holding states sensed danger in letting
free Negroes vote, and began to disfranchise
them. By <date>1834</date>no Negroes could vote in the  
</p></Narrator>
<p>
<Narrator>NARRATOR (cont'd): <p>South, and some Northern states like Penn-
sylvania and Indiana denied them the ballot,
too. But colored men in <state>New York</state>could
vote if they own property and had lived
here for three years. This man could vote. </p></Narrator>
</p>
    <actorName>FRAUNCES: And I <handNotes>
        <handNote medium="black-ink">could</handNote></handNotes>vote.--- </actorName> <!--include the handwritten correction here-->


</xml>






